Louise Bradley and Elizabeth Bishop Correspondence, 1925-1950 2014.003.0001
Wylie House Museum
Louise Bradley and Elizabeth Bishop Correspondence
1925-1950
Wylie House Museum
Louise Bradley
Elizabeth Bishop
2014.003.0001
.5 cubic feet 1 small box
lb:
Louise Bradley was the great-granddaughter of Rebecca and Theophilus A. Wylie. She was born and lived her whole life in Arlington, Massachusetts. Louise met future poet Elizabeth Bishop in the mid-1920s at Camp Chequesset on Cape Cod. The two exchanged letters for several years.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research. Advance notice is required.
Biographical Note/Administrative History
Louise Bradley (1908 – 1979) was the only daughter of Morton C. and Marie Bradley. She attended Indiana University for one year, then transferred to and graduated from Radcliff College. She worked for Raytheon Corporation and travelled widely. She never married and lived her whole life in her parents' home. Elizabeth Bishop (1911-1979) was a poet and author of short stories. Due to her father's early death and her mother's mental illness, Bishop was raised by a succession of family members. In 1930 she entered Vassar College where her poetry writing was fostered. Over the course of her career, she served as the Poet Laureate of the United States (1949-1950) and was the recipient of several awards including the Pulitzer Prize of Poetry (1956), National Book Winner (1970), the Neustadt International Prize for Literature (1976), and two Guggenheim Fellowships (1947 and 1978). Louise Bradley and Elizabeth Bishop met at Camp Chequesset on Cape Cod during the mid-1920s and continued to exchange letters for several years.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Scope and Content Note
This collection of personal correspondence was bequeathed to Wylie House Museum, Indiana University by Morton C. Bradley, Jr., a great-grandson of Theophilus A. and Rebecca D. Wylie, upon his death in September 2004. The collection is arranged chronologically. There are thirty-one letters written by Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley. A portion of the letters are dated 1925-1933 while others are undated fragments. In the letters, Bishop writes about her schoolwork, summer camp, books, shared interests, and shares a few piece of her early poetry.
Related Material
Additional Wylie family materials may be accessed in the Indiana University Archives Wylie House Collections.
Acquisition Information
Bequeathed to Wylie House Museum by Morton C. Bradley, Jr., great-grandson of Theophilus Adam Wylie.
American literature --20th Century; Women poets, American; 20th Century --Correspondence; Cape Cod Camp Chequesset; Bradley, Louise, 1908-1979 --Archives.; Bradley, Louise, 1908-1979 --Correspondence.; Bishop, Elizabeth, --1911-1979; Bishop, Elizabeth, --1911-1979 --Correspondence
- Louise Bradley and Elizabeth Bishop Correspondence, 1925-1950 (Box 1)
  - 1925
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, August 5, 1925
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, September 17, 1925
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, November 16, 1925
  - 1926
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, January 5, 1926
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley envelope only, March 30?, 1926
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, July 12, 1926
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, August 29, 1926
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, November 16, 1926
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, November 17, 1926
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, December 5, 1926
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [postmarked October 16, 1926]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley envelope only, [postmarked January 5, 1927]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, January 14, 1926
  - 1927
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [postmarked January 3, 1927]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, April 3, 1927
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, April 19, 1927
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, June 14, 1927
  - 1928
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [postmarked January 3, 1928]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [postmarked March 5, 1928]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, June 27, 1928
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, July 17, 1928
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, July 21, 1928
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley envelope only, [postmarked August 22, 1928]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [postmarked October 1, 1928]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, November 28, 1928
  - 1929
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, March 1, 1929
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [postmarked March 31, 1929]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, April 14, 1929
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Mrs. Bradley Thursday evening, [postmarked June 23, 1930]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley Thursday night, [postmarked June 23, 1929]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, July 12, 1929
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [postmarked August 19, 1929]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley envelope only, [postmarked September 2, 1929]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley Monday night, [postmarked September 10, 1929]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley envelope only, [postmarked October 13, 1929]
  - 1930
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley envelope only, [postmarked February 17, 1930]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley envelope only, [postmarked February 17, 1930]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, June 3, 1930
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley Tuesday night, [postmarked July 16, 1930]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley Sunday morning, [postmarked December 7, 1930]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [postmarked December 23, 1930]
  - 1931
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley Thursday morning, [postmarked January 9, 1931]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley envelope only, [postmarked February 8, 1931]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, July 27, 1931
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley Monday night, [postmarked September 15, 1931]
  - 1932
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, June 25, 1932
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, December 30, 1932
  - 1933
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, June 28, 1933
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, postcard Cuttyhunk, [postmarked July 16, 1933]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, August 18, 1933
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, September 6, 1933
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley Monday night, [postmarked September 26, 1933]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, Novemeber 6, 1933
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, December 28, 1933
  - 1934
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley envelope only, [postmarked January 12, 1934]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, February 4, 1934; February 11, 1934
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, March 22, 1934
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, June 20, 1934
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [August] 8, 1934
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [postmarked August 5, 1934]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, September 11, 1934
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, December 28, 1934
  - 1935
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, September 13, 1935
  - 1943
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [postmarked December 21, 1943]
  - 1950
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, January 12, 1950
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, August 8, 1950
  - Undated
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [Louise labeled this one 1929]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [Undated but it could be as early as or early as ], December 1926; 1927
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [ca. 1930, summer]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [ca. 1928?]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [Undated fragment or note]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [Undated fragment or note]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [Undated]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [Probably 1927]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [Probably 1926-1928]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [Undated]
    - Elizabeth Bishop to Louise Bradley, [Undated]